<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NeuroSnippets</title>
    <link>https://neurosnippets.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on NeuroSnippets</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://neurosnippets.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Interactive brain networks</title>
      <link>https://neurosnippets.com/posts/interactive-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neurosnippets.com/posts/interactive-network/</guid>
      <description>If you don&amp;rsquo;t make it interactive, enjoy only half I spent already a few posts on the topic of making ordinary stuff interactive, and despite the chances of literally wooing people when they see the final results, I think the final result is not the biggest selling point of interactive visualization. I think that what really makes interactive visualization great is the fact that makes it easier to explore the data without having to minimize the Jupyter Notebook, opening the terminal, looking for the file, opening fsleyes, and, wait, what was that I wanted to look at?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The skull-strip club: quick visual skull-stripping with FSL BET and Streamlit</title>
      <link>https://neurosnippets.com/posts/quick-stripper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neurosnippets.com/posts/quick-stripper/</guid>
      <description>You can leave your brain on One of the first steps almost every neuroimaging pipeline has to do is skull-stripping, to free the brain from its cage and start doing registration, segmentation, *insert here any processing you are into* , the list is long. There are many tools to accomplish that, I personally use FreeSurfer and despite the associated time cost (FastSurfer may be a solution though) I am happy about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grind those brains! Diffusion MRI preprocessing with papermill</title>
      <link>https://neurosnippets.com/posts/papermill-preproc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neurosnippets.com/posts/papermill-preproc/</guid>
      <description>Notebooks: you love them or you hate them Notebooks are an interesting beast: they have become extremely diverse and popular, everyone loves them, from declared non-programmers to enthusiastic pythonistas, from Kaggle fans to scientists. Well, that&amp;rsquo;s not exactly true: notebooks are actually one of those things that you end up loving them or strongly feeling against them - with indifference being very rare and usually due to not having interacted with them a lot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Histogrammers: a dashboard to quickly check MRI data</title>
      <link>https://neurosnippets.com/posts/mri-histogram/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neurosnippets.com/posts/mri-histogram/</guid>
      <description>All it takes is an ROI When one is dealing with MRI data (especially in the case of quantitative MRI), it is usually a good idea to check how the data are distributed. An example: you picked a myelin water fraction (MWF) map - it is reasonable to expect that the values will be higher in white matter than in grey matter. After this very first quality check, probably you may want to check how things change in different white matter structures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unleashing the dragon: running MRtrix3 in Google Colab</title>
      <link>https://neurosnippets.com/posts/mrtrix-in-colab/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neurosnippets.com/posts/mrtrix-in-colab/</guid>
      <description>A day in the life of browsers A random thought crossed my mind last week: with Javascript at the top of programming languages rankings and with so many notebook systems covering most needs, how far are we from doing almost everything in a browser? Do we actually want to do everything in a browser? Postponing the dystopian consequences to the next Black Mirror season, it is true that browsers have become so universal that it makes sense to give access to resources through them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One container to rule them all: FSL-FIX in a box</title>
      <link>https://neurosnippets.com/posts/fslfix-in-a-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neurosnippets.com/posts/fslfix-in-a-box/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Use a container&amp;rdquo; is the new &amp;ldquo;You need a virtual machine&amp;rdquo; I have to be sincere: the first time I heard about containers I was not impressed. It sounded like an exotic approach, and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see why would you need that. A few years later, I have changed my mind a lot about it: not only containers can be used to create reproducible workflows, but they are also useful in several applications (taken to the extreme in some cases).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive treemaps for interactive reviews</title>
      <link>https://neurosnippets.com/posts/interactive-treemaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neurosnippets.com/posts/interactive-treemaps/</guid>
      <description>Beyond rows and columns If you think about a literature review or a meta-analysis, your expectation in terms of format probably reflects the following description: a PDF file containing a large table with the main details from the surveyed studies. This immediate association is the result of some sort of immutability in time of reviews, and more in general scientific papers. But there is no reason for papers to be conservative, static objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a glass brain</title>
      <link>https://neurosnippets.com/posts/glass-brain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neurosnippets.com/posts/glass-brain/</guid>
      <description>Everything looks better with glass How can we give the deserved credit to white matter pathways in diffusion MRI? Easy: let&amp;rsquo;s throw away everything besides white matter. Jokes aside, tractography can already be a lot to digest, and sometimes we just need a rough reference to understand what we are looking at. If it is true that less is more, glass brains are a simple yet effective idea. In this post, I want to explore one way to make a smooth brain proposed by Thijs Dhollander: using the average from several brain masks, and then playing around with image operations to obtain a smooth and thin silhouette.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://neurosnippets.com/about_me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neurosnippets.com/about_me/</guid>
      <description>Biosketch I am on a quest for better maps of the brain. A biomedical engineer by training, I got my BSc from the University of Rome &amp;ldquo;Sapienza&amp;rdquo; in 2011, followed by a MSc from the University of Rome &amp;ldquo;Roma Tre&amp;rdquo; in 2013. My PhD has been focused on multimodal brain connectivity using a combination of MRI and non-invasive stimulation, collaborating with the Italian National Institute of Health, the Santa Lucia Foundation and the University of Sussex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://neurosnippets.com/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neurosnippets.com/research/</guid>
      <description>Research vision: brain maps, cartograms and blueprints A constant element in my research are brain maps. What is a brain map? Is the result of some MRI acquisition? In a sense, even a simple clinical scan allows us to look at something hidden in our skull. However, the brain has such a complex structure, articulated in so many levels, that a map cannot be uniquely defined. Even the holy grail of hardcore connectomics, a full diagram of every synapsis, would still be missing elements: what about the myelin?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
