<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>python on NeuroSnippets</title>
    <link>https://neurosnippets.com/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in python on NeuroSnippets</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://neurosnippets.com/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Grind those brains! Diffusion MRI preprocessing with papermill</title>
      <link>https://neurosnippets.com/posts/papermill-preproc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neurosnippets.com/posts/papermill-preproc/</guid>
      <description>Notebooks: you love them or you hate them Notebooks are an interesting beast: they have become extremely diverse and popular, everyone loves them, from declared non-programmers to enthusiastic pythonistas, from Kaggle fans to scientists. Well, that&amp;rsquo;s not exactly true: notebooks are actually one of those things that you end up loving them or strongly feeling against them - with indifference being very rare and usually due to not having interacted with them a lot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Histogrammers: a dashboard to quickly check MRI data</title>
      <link>https://neurosnippets.com/posts/mri-histogram/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neurosnippets.com/posts/mri-histogram/</guid>
      <description>All it takes is an ROI When one is dealing with MRI data (especially in the case of quantitative MRI), it is usually a good idea to check how the data are distributed. An example: you picked a myelin water fraction (MWF) map - it is reasonable to expect that the values will be higher in white matter than in grey matter. After this very first quality check, probably you may want to check how things change in different white matter structures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive treemaps for interactive reviews</title>
      <link>https://neurosnippets.com/posts/interactive-treemaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neurosnippets.com/posts/interactive-treemaps/</guid>
      <description>Beyond rows and columns If you think about a literature review or a meta-analysis, your expectation in terms of format probably reflects the following description: a PDF file containing a large table with the main details from the surveyed studies. This immediate association is the result of some sort of immutability in time of reviews, and more in general scientific papers. But there is no reason for papers to be conservative, static objects.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
