<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>brainviz on NeuroSnippets</title>
    <link>https://neurosnippets.com/tags/brainviz/</link>
    <description>Recent content in brainviz on NeuroSnippets</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://neurosnippets.com/tags/brainviz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The skull-strip club: quick visual skull-stripping with FSL BET and Streamlit</title>
      <link>https://neurosnippets.com/posts/quick-stripper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neurosnippets.com/posts/quick-stripper/</guid>
      <description>You can leave your brain on One of the first steps almost every neuroimaging pipeline has to do is skull-stripping, to free the brain from its cage and start doing registration, segmentation, *insert here any processing you are into* , the list is long. There are many tools to accomplish that, I personally use FreeSurfer and despite the associated time cost (FastSurfer may be a solution though) I am happy about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Histogrammers: a dashboard to quickly check MRI data</title>
      <link>https://neurosnippets.com/posts/mri-histogram/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neurosnippets.com/posts/mri-histogram/</guid>
      <description>All it takes is an ROI When one is dealing with MRI data (especially in the case of quantitative MRI), it is usually a good idea to check how the data are distributed. An example: you picked a myelin water fraction (MWF) map - it is reasonable to expect that the values will be higher in white matter than in grey matter. After this very first quality check, probably you may want to check how things change in different white matter structures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a glass brain</title>
      <link>https://neurosnippets.com/posts/glass-brain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neurosnippets.com/posts/glass-brain/</guid>
      <description>Everything looks better with glass How can we give the deserved credit to white matter pathways in diffusion MRI? Easy: let&amp;rsquo;s throw away everything besides white matter. Jokes aside, tractography can already be a lot to digest, and sometimes we just need a rough reference to understand what we are looking at. If it is true that less is more, glass brains are a simple yet effective idea. In this post, I want to explore one way to make a smooth brain proposed by Thijs Dhollander: using the average from several brain masks, and then playing around with image operations to obtain a smooth and thin silhouette.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
