<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MRtrix3 on NeuroSnippets</title>
    <link>https://neurosnippets.com/tags/mrtrix3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MRtrix3 on NeuroSnippets</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://neurosnippets.com/tags/mrtrix3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Every bundle counts - A recipe for bundle-wise, myelin-weighted connectomes</title>
      <link>https://neurosnippets.com/posts/bundle-connectome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neurosnippets.com/posts/bundle-connectome/</guid>
      <description>Esoteric connectomes Graphs are straightforward objects: you have a bunch of nodes, some of them are inter-connected by edges, and it all makes sense. It is in real-world networks that things become complicated: what&amp;rsquo;s a node? What&amp;rsquo;s an edge? When it comes to the brain, the answers to these questions depend on what scale one is targeting, and what tools has available. For whole-brain, structural connectivity, the usual approach is to use tractography, and then count how many streamlines there are between each pair of regions to weight the associated graph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grind those brains! Diffusion MRI preprocessing with papermill</title>
      <link>https://neurosnippets.com/posts/papermill-preproc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neurosnippets.com/posts/papermill-preproc/</guid>
      <description>Notebooks: you love them or you hate them Notebooks are an interesting beast: they have become extremely diverse and popular, everyone loves them, from declared non-programmers to enthusiastic pythonistas, from Kaggle fans to scientists. Well, that&amp;rsquo;s not exactly true: notebooks are actually one of those things that you end up loving them or strongly feeling against them - with indifference being very rare and usually due to not having interacted with them a lot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unleashing the dragon: running MRtrix3 in Google Colab</title>
      <link>https://neurosnippets.com/posts/mrtrix-in-colab/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neurosnippets.com/posts/mrtrix-in-colab/</guid>
      <description>A day in the life of browsers A random thought crossed my mind last week: with Javascript at the top of programming languages rankings and with so many notebook systems covering most needs, how far are we from doing almost everything in a browser? Do we actually want to do everything in a browser? Postponing the dystopian consequences to the next Black Mirror season, it is true that browsers have become so universal that it makes sense to give access to resources through them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a glass brain</title>
      <link>https://neurosnippets.com/posts/glass-brain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neurosnippets.com/posts/glass-brain/</guid>
      <description>Everything looks better with glass How can we give the deserved credit to white matter pathways in diffusion MRI? Easy: let&amp;rsquo;s throw away everything besides white matter. Jokes aside, tractography can already be a lot to digest, and sometimes we just need a rough reference to understand what we are looking at. If it is true that less is more, glass brains are a simple yet effective idea. In this post, I want to explore one way to make a smooth brain proposed by Thijs Dhollander: using the average from several brain masks, and then playing around with image operations to obtain a smooth and thin silhouette.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
